UNITE HERE Audio-Visual Materials 6200 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE HERE Audio-Visual Materials
2004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE HERE
6200 AV
1.56 cubic feet
1.6 linear ft.
Audiovisual material.
7672124
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 02, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 27, 2015
Biographical / Historical
UNITE HERE is a labor union in the United States and Canada, that was formed in 2004 by the merger of the Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees (UNITE) and Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE). The membership is made up mainly of workers in the hotel, food service, laundry, warehouse, and casino gaming industries.
In 2005, UNITE HERE left the AFL-CIO and joined the Change to Win Federation along with other unions including the Teamsters, SEIU and the UFCW. In may 2009, Bruce Raynor, president, left UNITE HERE, taking with hiim several local unions and between 105,000 and 150,000 members. They formed Workers United.
September 17, 2009, UNITE HERE announced that it would re-join the AFL-CIO.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6200: UNITE HERE Records
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Textile workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; Textile Workers Union of America; UNITE HERE (Organization)
7672124
- Working together for a better future, 1 (Box 1)
- Working together for a better future, 2 (Box 1)
- Working together for a better future, 3 (Box 1)
- Working together for a better future, 4 (Box 1)
- Fior Roman - UNITE HERE Convention video, 5 (Box 1)
- Merger Convention Highlights 2004, 6 (Box 1)
- Merger Convention Highlights 2004, 7 (Box 1)
- Merger Convention Highlights 2004, 8 (Box 1)
- We do the work "Sewing our future", 9 (Box 1)
- Land of Promise, 10 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  My name is Mary Brown; Hail to the Chief
- Looking Back Moving Forward, 11 (Box 1)
- Bernice Yeung's radio piece about 9/11, 2001 (Box 2)
- Looking back moving forward (Box 3)
- Chinese Christian Herald Crusades -- 20th Anniversary (2002) (Box 4)
- UNITE!, Paul Shapiro (Box 5)
- Music for living collection (Box 6)